publitas.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Statement

This privacy policy concerns the processing of personal data by the public websites publitas.com (“Publitas website”), app.publitas.com (“Publitas CMS”) and support.publitas.com (“Publitas support”) as well as the processing of personal data when communicating with us through email or phone.

Sections 1, 2 and 3 below provide an overview of the collection and use of personal data by Publitas and the purposes for which this data is being used. We always seek to find a balance between your fundamental right to privacy and the legitimate interests of Publitas, in compliance with European regulations.

## 1\. Your data in online publications

When you’re viewing our customers’ online publications, Publitas _does not collect or process any personal data_ , except for your IP address which is temporarily stored in our system for security purposes only.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the processing of personal data about end users by our customers. We have no control over our customers’ information privacy practices. If you are viewing an online publication or third party website, you should refer to their privacy policy for information about how they process your personal data.

## 2\. Your data related to our websites, services and your account

### A. When browsing our websites

When you visit our websites, we automatically collect information about how you interact with our website for the sole purpose of analyzing anonymous website usage and identifying improvements. This information includes cookies, date and time of your visit, pages viewed and generic information about the technology used to access our site. We may also use your IP address to derive what country you’re currently in to show you the correct pricing information.

A third party provider called Intercom delivers our integrated chat solution on our website. Intercom sets cookies and tracks what page you’re on for the purpose of showing and hiding the chat window when relevant.

We engage third parties like social- and advertising platforms that set cookies and analyze your browsing behaviour in order to show ads to internet users with similar browsing behaviour. The information collected by these third parties does not include personal information that enables you to be specifically identified (e.g. by reference to your name or email address).

We may ask for your consent to use third parties like social- and advertising platforms that set cookies so we can show you relevant ads based on how you’ve browsed our website.

### B. When you fill out an online form, chat with us on our website or sign up for a trial

Contact data you provide through online forms on our website, the chat widget or the trial signup forms (including your email address) will be used to follow-up on your request and/or provide you access to your trial account. For this same purpose, we may keep records of our communication with you and track interactions with our email messages (such as opening). We may also use third parties like social- and advertising platforms that set cookies so we can show you relevant ads about your download or trial.

### C. When we contact you about our services

Our sales and marketing team may come across your details or your company’s details online in our search for companies we think we can add value to with our services. In doing so, we may store your name, business contact information (such as work email address), information about your position and information about your company in our systems. We will also keep records of our communication with you and track interactions with our email messages (such as opening). We do this so we can contact you about our services through email and/or phone and effectively follow-up on our communication with you.

### D. When you are a customer or are becoming a customer

For Publitas customers, employees of Publitas customers or prospective customers with whom we are in an active bilateral contact, we collect and use the categories of information listed below because we either have a direct contract with you or because you work for a company we have a contract with. 

  1. We may collect your name and basic contact information in order to contact you about your contract and/or your account and to respond to incoming requests more effectively. We may also use your contact information to send you a customer satisfaction survey after you’ve been in contact with us.
  2. We may keep records of our communication with you and track interactions with our email messages (such as opening). We do this so we can contact you about our services and effectively follow-up on our communication with you.
  3. We may collect billing information in order to invoice our services and process payments.
  4. We may obtain information from social networking sites (eg. LinkedIn), in order to make our communication to you more relevant.

### E. When you create, activate and use your user account

When you create or activate your account, we will collect basic information about you in order to properly identify you and provide you access to our system. The email address you provide may also be used to contact you about your use of the system, which includes service messages and occasional customer satisfaction surveys.

When using your account, we collect information about how you use your account. This includes cookies, date and time of access, navigation events and mouse clicks. We may use this information in order to make sure you only receive relevant service messages (eg. about features you actually use) and to analyse usage of the service and identify improvements.

## 3\. Your data related to working at Publitas

### A. When you apply for a job

When you apply for a job, we may store your name, contact information (such as email address) and career history and interests in our systems. We will also keep records of our communication with you. We do this so we can contact you about relevant positions at our company and effectively follow-up on our communication with you.

Because over 50% of the company works location-independent, our interview process typically involves video calls which we may record in order to share them with team members or other people relevant to the position you’re applying for. We will always inform you about the possibility of recording before or at the beginning of the call.

Any additional information you provide during the interview process will only be used for the purpose of serving the interview process and will never be shared outside of Publitas.

### B. When we contact you about working for Publitas

Because we’re always on the lookout for talent, we may come across your details on a social networking site or other website. In doing so, we may store your name, contact information (such as email address) and career history and interests in our systems. We will also keep records of our communication with you. We do this so we can contact you about relevant positions at our company and effectively follow-up on our communication with you.

## 4\. How long we store your data

Unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, personal data is kept in accordance with our internal retention policy and kept only for as long as necessary to fulfil legitimate processing purposes or as may be necessary to comply with any other legal obligation.

You can always reach out to us if you’d like us to remove any data we have from you (also refer to section 6)

## 5\. Sharing your data with third parties

We believe in focus, which means we may share your information with third parties specialized in certain tasks related to your information. This includes our infrastructure providers, third parties for billing, email and phone communications, customer support, product analytics and project management. We make sure that all third parties we work with meet our standards in terms of information security and privacy.

### Third parties outside the EU

We may transfer your personal information to other countries outside the European Union and make it accessible to to other companies within the Publitas group of companies and third party service providers internationally. We will protect your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy wherever it is processed.

## 6\. Your data, your rights

At any time, you have the right to control if and how we use your personal data. This means you have the right to:

  1. withdraw consent where previously given; and
  2. request restriction of processing; and
  3. request access to your data; and
  4. request to update your data; and
  5. request to delete or de-identify your data; and
  6. request your data in a portable file; and
  7. lodge a complaint

For all requests regarding your data, you can contact us using the details below and we’ll get back to you within 20 working days.

Our information  
Publitas.com B.V.  
Zeeburgerpad 5  
1018AH Amsterdam  
privacy@publitas.com  

_This privacy statement was updated in June 2018. When we change the policy on how collected data on this website is treated, we will announce this through an alteration of our privacy statement._
